Dubofsky, Melvyn Papers 6218
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Course material, exams (continued). Drafts of articles, early correspondence. (Box 15)
  - LH Course Notes Exams and Research Topics (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Exams Folder Sample (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - NYC Labor + Politics, 1910-1918 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - 1975: AHA Convention Session Class Consciousness: American Worker (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - 1976 AHA Convention and 1977 OAH Convention Plans (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Hayward Essay Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Leadville Conflict, 1896-1897 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Labor History Readings Book (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Socialism and Labor 1900-1918 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - D Webster and American Eco. Growth - Management (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - D Webster + American Economic Growth (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - J Garrety: Bio Dict. Mother Jones (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - PNQ + Hanley (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Barnum File (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - DAB Supp. - R. Chaplin Bio. (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - DAB - Robert Hunter (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - DAB Dorothy Jacobs Bellaco Sketch (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - D De Leon: Britannica (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - J A Garrety - WD Hayward Sketch (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - A Whitmon Bio Dic. Big Bill Hayward (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - K R O Hare Bio Sketch (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - DAB - Herbert Mahler (Box 15, Folder 37)
- IWW research material. (Box 16)
  - Bisbie Photos and Negs (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Photos (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Publishers for IWW Ms. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Fed. Govt and IWW H Mahler (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - IWW Materials to be Read (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - IWW Materials From N/A - List (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - IWW Citations to Check (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - IWW Buses (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Joe Hill Items (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - IWW and WFM in Western Archive and Libraries correspondence (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - R Brazier (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - C. C. Colorado, 1894 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - 1896 Leadville Strike Notes (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - C. C. Colorado, 1903-1904 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - IWW - industry Syndication (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - IWW Idealogy J Panama's Dream (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Spokane Free Speech Fight, 1910 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    Jan 9
  - Fresno Free Speech Fight, 1910-1911 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - IWW and San Diego Free Speech Fight, 1912 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    May 6 - Sept 5
  - McKees Rocks, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Natl Rip Law (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - F Bohn on 1911 Convention and Future of IWW (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Lawrence Strike (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Festor and Berning from Within (Box 16, Folder 24)
    nov 11
  - 1905 IWW Convention (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - WFM and IWW 1907-1908 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - IWW - 1907-1908 Growth and 1908 Convention Reports + dilate (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - R Tugnell on Nature of IWW, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - CIR - IWW Testimony - Hayward St. (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Mag Articles on IWW (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - IWW + Paterson (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - IWW + NY, 1914 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Butte Factional conflict, IWW + WFM, 1914 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - IWW in CALIF, 1914 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - 1914 - Organization Dec. Tactical Debate (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Fed Govt + IWW Calif., 1915 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    Nov 26
  - IWW + Mesaba Strike, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - IWW and Everett, 1916-1917 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Fed. Got + IWW Wash State, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Western State and IWW Geo. Bill Memos (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - IWW in Wash State Reports (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - IWW and Butte Davies Reports, 1918 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - T Veblen IWW and Farm Labor, 1918 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Fed. Govt and IWW Oregon (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Public and IWW 1917 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Fed Govt and IWW Montana, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 46)
    aug 29
  - IWW and Arizona MMWU Leaflets (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Fed. Govt and IWW Okla., 1917 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    Dec 5
  - IWW and Arizona F Frankfurter Rule (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - IWW and Arizona B of I Report, 1918 (Box 16, Folder 50)
    Jan 8
  - IWW and Arizona Fed. Survey of Conditions, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Fed Govt and IWW Globe Reports + Speech, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 52)
    June - July
  - IWW and Arizona Jerome Loyalty League (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Fed Govt and IWW Hayward Case (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - E G Flynn, et al. and Hayward Case, 1917-1918 (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - Geo., 1916-1918 (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - Fed. Govt. and IWW Sacramento Case (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - Fed. Govt. and IWW T Pollock Case (Box 16, Folder 58)
  - IWW Letters Miscellaneous (Box 16, Folder 59)
  - Genl. Defense IWW (Box 16, Folder 60)
  - Fed. Govt and IWW Wichita Case (Box 16, Folder 61)
  - IWW Pardon Appeals (Box 16, Folder 62)
  - IWW and NW Genl Strike Report, 1919 (Box 16, Folder 63)
    Jan 24
  - IWW and Fed Prisoners, 1919 (Box 16, Folder 64)
  - IWW and Centralia, 1919 (Box 16, Folder 65)
  - Fed. Govt and IWW Wash State, 1918-1919 (Box 16, Folder 66)
  - IWW and Domestics Letter Organizers, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 67)
  - IWW Convention Proceedings, 1919-1955 (Box 16, Folder 68)
  - IWW Proceedings, 1966-1968 (Box 16, Folder 69)
  - Tom Mann Notes (Box 16, Folder 70)
  - US Ind. Comm. (Box 16, Folder 71)
  - IWW and Arizona Pres. Mediation Comm. On Bisbie Deportation (Box 16, Folder 72)
  - IWW and Arizona Pres. Comm. On Clifton Morenci (Box 16, Folder 73)
  - AFL and IWW Gompers NW Lumber, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 74)
    Aug 22
  - Report of Pres. Mediation comm (Box 16, Folder 75)
  - IWW and Arizona Fed Govt., 1918 (Box 16, Folder 76)
    March 22
  - G Vaneveer to W Wilson and Crul on IWW (Box 16, Folder 77)
  - Hayward and AFL - IWW Contract, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 78)
  - F P Walsh on WD Hayward and Geo. Speech, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 79)
  - W D Hayward - Bio Materials (Box 16, Folder 80)
  - Hayward Trial Boise Testimony and Materials, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 81)
- IWW research material (continued). (Box 17)
  - Labor Journal (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - K Klare "Judicial Deindustrialization of Wagner Act" MLR (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - WWII Labor + Industrial - Military Complex (Kastem) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - NLRA, Industrial Unionism (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Texas + Buffalo Law Review, Smith Committee and the NLRB Case (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Law Review (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Misc Law Reviews (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - US Presidential Memoirs (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - More US Presidential memoirs (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Articles and papers about Jimmy Carter, reviews of Melvyn Dubofsky's books and one general correspondence, files (Box 18)
  - General corres. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous and Excess Labor Documents (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Vol 3 - I (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Vol 2 - II (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - CIO, NYC, Socialist, Etc. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Working Paper 1978, John Lewis (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Reviews: We Shall Be all (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Reviews: When Workers Organize (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Dubofsky (Box 18, Folder 9)
- IWW research notes (Box 19)
  - Western Federation of Miners (Box 19, Folder 1)
    5x8" Index cards
- IWW research notes (continued). MD Dissertation. (Box 20)
  - IWW (Box 20, Folder 1)
    5x8" Paper Slips
- IWW research material (Box 21)
  - WFM and IWW (Box 21, Folder 1)
    5x8" Paper slips and index cards
- General correspondence (Labor History editorial board), evaluation of articles. (Box 22)
  - Melvyn Dubofsky Email Box 22 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Corres. History Topics (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Labor History Editorial Board - May 1980 Dan Leab (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - LH Editorial File (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Corres., 1992 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Catherine Pollack CIO executive board minutes. Coeur d'Alene strike (yellow box). Pacific Northwest Lumber Company labor relations (Box 23)
  - Microfilm (Box 23, Folder 1)
- AFL-CIO papers - Commission on Industrial Relations 1912-1915, papers of NWLB (WW I) Bureau of Industrial Research on Early American Labor History. (Box 24)
  - Microfilm reels University Publications of America/ Frederick, MD (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Microfilm - American Federation of Labor Records (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous business correspondence, proposals (includes portions of PBS series on US labor). (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, Current (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Mel: Israel Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Neil Basen Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - E. Rosslack: Ed TV - LH Semis (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Lee Benson, DSOC History Conf. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Harry Matthews, LIHE (NEH) (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Fulbright Application Tel Aviv U, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - T Brandon: Film Library Quarterly (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Misc., Research (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Univ. Pub. Of America Labor Studies Service - Gen. Ed. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - P-H Text: U.S. Service, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - DOL-ETI Labor Relation Project (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Lecture: Labor Movement in Crisis: Historian's Prospects (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - SUNY Binghamton - Job (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - 20th C Text - P-H Corres. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - 20th C J.C. Textbook - Social + Cultural History (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - B. Palmer, McGill U Canadian W.C. Conference (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Dubofsky Press (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Marty Feldman Corres. File (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - M Lapitsky (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Van Tine Corres. (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Columbia Seminar in W-C History (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Stories and Teleplays (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - NEH 1981 Summer Seminar Schedule (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - NYS Labor History Conference, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    June 10
  - Routledge: LH Articles Series (Box 26, Folder 26)
- Project correspondence, manuscript drafts, notes. (Box 27)
  - Dist. Prof. Promotions File (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Museum/Archives (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - U of NC Press Book Contract, Labor (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - HD Industrialism + Workers 3rd Edition (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Greenword Press: Worker Reference Project (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - UPA (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Gompers Paper (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - 1997-1998 Disting Fulbright (Bologna, Florence) (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - MD Essays: U of Illinois Contract (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - New Deal and Labor (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - New Deal and Labor 1937-1941 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Sponsored Funds completed Payroll (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Misc. Corres 1900-1916 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Columbia U OHP Notes on JLL (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Notes on Wilson Admin and Labor (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Mss. Book, Odds and Ends (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - F Forms (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Labor Policies, 1920s Ch.4 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Notes: Fed Labor Policy 1870s (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Anthracite Strike, etc. (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Revs: Hard Work and WSBA (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - W. H. Taft ABA Essay (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Labor Historians (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Paper: Not So "Turbulent Years": Workers in 1930s (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Recent Approaches to US Labor History - Fredonia Paper (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - ILR Course, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - L.H.: Labor + Politics, 1880-1900 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - L.H.: Employers, Workers, + the Community (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - The Pre-industrial Worker L.H. (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - L.H. Workers in Jacksonian Era (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - L.H.: Black Workers (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - L.H.: Labor in War + Reconstruction (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - W. C. History, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - History 183: Fall, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - L.H. Syllabi and Reading Lists (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - History 183, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - Labor History: Course Intro and General Theories (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - UPA (Box 27, Folder 38)
- Correspondence and essays. (Box 28)
  - Misc. Dubofsky Papers (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Fox-Genovese (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - M.D. Essays (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Dubofsky, Netherlands (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Garland: US Labor Conflict (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Visiting Professorships - Salzburg, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Publication Contracts and Royalty Correspondence, 1970-1990 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - New York State Labor History Association, 1976-1983 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Invitations, 1982-1989 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Twenty-First Century Press Correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Wagnleitner, Reinhold, 1990-1994 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 1998-2009 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Retirement and Bartle Professorship, 2002-2010 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Symposiums, 2005-2008 (Box 28, Folder 14)
- Melvin Dubofsky Computer files (Box 29)
- Dubofsky E-mail (Box 30)
- Eudora and Microsoft Outlook Express email files relating to Labor History, the Labor History Society, and the Taft Prize. (Box 31)